

DATA SCIENTIST IN THE MAKING

Apartment 20, St. James's Court, Echlin Street, Dublin 8

🛘 (+353) 89-4960-450 | 🗷 amukesh.mk@gmail.com | 🌴 mukeshmk.github.io | 📮 mukeshmk | 📓 mukesh-a | 🗖 mukeshmk95

Personal Summary _____

A Master's in Data Science student from Trinity College of Dublin, with 2 years of work experience as an Application Engineer at Oracle India, Pvt. Ltd. Highly skilled in Machine Learning, Data Analytics, and Creative Thinking. Seeking a challenging career as a Data Scientist to apply my knowledge and skills by tackling real-world issues. I am available for employment upon submission of my thesis in August 2020.

Skills

Programming: Python, Java, R, Processing, C++, C, SQL, PL/SQL

Frameworks: Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow, Flask, Spring, Hibernate, Mockito, REST

Tools & IDE's: Intellij, Eclipse, SQL Developer, Ant, Oracle12c, MySQL

Server & Version Control: Oracle Weblogic12c, git, GitHub, TortoiseHG

Education

Trinity College of Dublin M.Sc. IN DATA SCIENCE

aiming for 1:1

2019 - 2020

Relevant Course Work: Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Artificial Intelligence, Optimisation Algorithms for Data Analysis, Knowledge and Data Engineering, Text Analysis, Applied Statistical Modelling, Data Visualisation

Thesis: Federated Meta-Learning: A Novel Approach for Algorithm Selection.

[] FMLearn, an application which allows the exchange of meta-data about machine learning models and data for the purpose of meta-learned algorithm selection and configuration.

Amrita School of Engineering

CGPA: 8.37/10.0

B.Tech. In Computer Science and Engineering

2013 - 2017

Relevant Course Work: Data Structures, Design and Analysis of Algorithm, Pattern Recognition, Data Mining and Warehousing, Database Management Systems, Software Engineering

Projects

Captcha Solver

🗖 captcha-solver

IMAGE AND AUDIO CAPTCHA SOLVER

Oct. 2019

• Parallelized image and audio captcha solver based on TensorFlow's Convolutional Neural Networks implementation.

BAN on AWS

🞧 ban-on-awscloud9

BODY AREA NETWORK SIMULATIONR

Nov. 2019

• Implementation of Body Area Network on Amazon AWS-IoT cloud9 Instances.

Connect 4

Connect-4

GAME BASED ON ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Jan. 2020 - May. 2020

• A multi-agent implementation of the game Connect-4 using MCTS, Minimax and Exptimax algorithms.

Sentiment Analysis

twitter-sentiment-analysis

TWITTER SENTIMENT ANALYSIS

Jan. 2020 - May. 2020

• An opinion poll where public tweets considered as an indicator to predict the actual election results.

Mukesh Arambakam

Publication

Jun 2020 7th ICML Workshop on Automated Machine Learning (AutoML),

link to publication

Federated Meta-Learning: Democratizing Algorithm Selection Across Disciplines and Software Libraries

Certifications _

2016 **Machine Learning**, Stanford University, Coursera

Cryptography I, Stanford University, Coursera

Online Certificate
Course Completed

Work Experience _____

Augray Private, Ltd.

DATA SCIENTIST INTERN

July. 2020 - Current

• Developing an Augmented Reality based "Try On" application

Oracle India Private, Ltd.

APPLICATIONS ENGINEER (IC-2)

June. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Certificate of Appreciation: For outstanding contribution to Prime Projects Product Development
- Lead the development in redesigning the security flow for the Product and introducing new features.
- Co-Designed and Developed an application which works across multiple platforms.
- Developed a micro-service which communicates between tenants in a Multi-Tenant Architecture.

Oracle India Private, Ltd.

APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER (IC-1)

July. 2017 - May. 2019

- Engineered multiple core features in the product Oracle Primavera Cloud.
- Optimized the product's filter framework for dynamic queries by 30% using Oracle's Query Builder framework.
- Developed an optimized search framework to retrieve data from the database using query optimization techniques.

Oracle India Private, Ltd.

GRADUATE INTERN

Jan. 2017 - June. 2017

- Worked as a Selenium Automation Engineer for **Oracle Primavera**.
- Briefly worked as a Quality Assurance Engineer.

Cisco Systems Private, Ltd.

INTERN

Oct 2016 - Mar 2017

- Worked on Platform Transformation for an internal Product: Cordys Process System.
- Designed the UX, Architecture and Schema Design for the application.

Hitachi Solutions, Ltd.

INTERN

July. 2016 - July. 2016

• Created a web application with an authentication system.

Extra-Curricular Activities

2016-17 Placement Representative, B. Tech CSE - B

 ${\bf 2016} \qquad {\bf Tech\{know\}logy\ Club},\ {\bf Conducted\ a\ workshop\ on\ } {\it Introduction\ to\ Open\ Source\ and\ git}$

2013-15 Class Representative, B. Tech CSE - B

2015 **Anokha 2k15**, worked in the Public Relations Department

Hobbies and Interest.

Reading Comics and Manga, Watching Anime, Playing the Piano, Basket Ball, Cycling